David Cheng

Senior Software Developer

Texas City, TX, United States

david.chengup@gmail.com

+1(601)975-2620

in linkedin.com/in/david-cheng-a07296355/

SUMMARY

As a senior software developer with more than 10 years experiences, I am responsible for building Full Stack Solutions from scratch for a lot of industries including E-learning platforms, Fintech, Healthcare and Finance. For example, the global healthcare industry that I have participated was valued at around \$12 billion in 2023 and is projected to reach \$20 billion by 2030. I am sure that I will delivery successful result in any kind of industry that you are planning to improve and move forwards.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Full Stack Developer/Lead

Sunny Isles, FL, US

Hivex | Aug 2023 - Dec 2024

- Led a team of 15 in the development of an online business server using React.js, Redux, Hooks, Bootstrap 5 and Pixi.js for a scalable and responsive front end
- Designed a scalable front-end architecture for serverless APIs and REST APIs using React.is. resulting in improved load times by 40% through optimized code structure and integration of **NoSOL** database.
- Built a backend using Node.js, Java, Python, and Golang following modern OOP practices, reducing server response times by 50% and increasing system scalability to handle up to 1 million concurrent users seamlessly.
- Integrated various AWS services including EC2, S3, AWS EKS, AWS SageMaker, and AWS **Lambda** to build a reliable, scalable cloud infrastructure.
- Created an innovative custom ChatGPT solution tailored to project requirements, resulting enhanced user interaction quality while decreasing manual intervention needs by over 35
- Delivered measurable benefits, enhancing key business areas by reducing API response time by 40%" and "improving user interaction by 30%.

The Software House | May 2022 – Jun 2023

- Developed E-Learning website for children, Wellness & Fitness website, Food Delivery & Ride Ordering Platform with React, Next.js as frontend and GoLang and C# as backend.
- Suggested robust and scalable backend solutions, ensuring high performance and security that optimized API response times by 60%, resulting in a smoother user experience.
- Advanced efficient payment processing workflows with **Stripe**, reducing transaction processing time by 40%, which resulted in a 25% increase in successful payments and a 15% boost in user satisfaction.
- Utilized project management tools such as Jira and Trello to streamline workflows and enhance project visibility.
- Launched OAuth authentication and two-factor authentication (2FA) to enhance user security and streamline login processes, ensuring the protection of user data.
- Proceeded code reviews, offering valuable feedback to enhance code quality and maintain coding standards using **GitLab** and **Bitbucket**.
- Executed the design of robust **CI/CD pipelines**, leveraging **Jenkins**, **Docker**, and **Kubernetes**, resulting in a significant reduction in software development and release cycles.

Software Engineer | Microservice

London, England

Pixelette Technology | Jan 2018 - Apr 2022

- Collaborated in the design and implementation of CI/CD and DevOps processes for agile projects, accelerating deployment frequency by 70% and reducing production errors by 40%.
- Worked with technologies and platforms such as Python, Java, Javascript, Git, Linux, Docker, Kubernetes, Ngnix, Azure Jenkins, AWS, used debugging tools like React-DevTools for faster debugging and reducing debugging time by 50%.
- Experienced on **TDD**, followed test-first methodology in refactoring projects, wrote unit and integration tests using **Jest**, **Mocha**, and **Cypress**, and test coverage was more than 80%.
- Implemented best practices in microservices architecture, enhancing scalability to handle a 200% increase in user traffic and boosting overall performance by reducing response times by 50%.
- Leveraged cloud services such as AWS, GCP, and DigitalOcean to deploy, scale, and manage
 infrastructure, reducing infrastructure costs by 35% and improving deployment speed by
 60%, while maintaining 99.99% system uptime.

Stockholm, Sweden

Middle Web Developer

OpenGeeksLab | Jan 2016 - Dec 2017

- Refactored event management and appointment management system for company internal members by migrating from HTML to Angular.
- Maintained a large web application using HTML/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP
 (Laravel) framework, and automated monthly supplier payments billing cycle using
 PHP and MySQL. Ran payment programs on a monthly basis and adjusted
 conditional business logic through a web interface.
- Turned mockups and designs into actual responsive websites and sliced or extracted the PSDs myself when asked, and finished responsive 3-5 pages in less than 72 hours, given specific time frames ranging from 3 to 5 days.
- Contributed to the successful delivery of projects on time and within budget, consistently meeting or exceeding client expectations.

EDUCATION

Aug 2010 – Dec 2015 University of North Texas
Bachelor's Degree, Computer science

TX, US

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript, Python, PHP, C#, Golang, Java
- Frontend: React.js, Next.js, Angular 2, Vue.js, Redux, Hooks, React Query, MUI, JQuery, BS5, Tailwind
- Backend: Node.js, Express.js, Nest.js, .NET, .NET Core, ASP.NET, Python, Django, Flask, FastAPI,
 Laravel, GraphQL
- Database: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, SQLite, MariaDB, Azure SQL, SQL server
- Cloud and DevOps: Amazon web services(AWS), Azure DevOps services, Google cloud platform,
 Docker, Kubernetes, CI/CD pipelines